Well, I look, I um
didn't trade up and we drafted an LSU
player, so there shouldn't be any
questions.
>> One one question. Do you consider
getting 219 back in the trade for Tony
Wilson trading down?
>> Well, do you guys
>> It's a big debate.
>> Yeah. Was this a mission pre-draft? The
emphasis on getting offensive weapons.
Did you expect before we started to to
walk away with four guys?
>> Um, I don't know that we expected four,
but look, we wanted to, you know, we
wanted to add in that area. We wanted to
add speed to our team, which we did. I
think, uh, you know, one thing I think
we we drafted a heck of a relay team,
uh, if we want to go that route. Um, so
look, I think there was a little
something for everyone, offense,
defense, and special teams. And and u,
you know, I think that's a good thing
for us.
>> What do you like about Jeremiah right
off the court?
>> Yeah, big uh people mover. Um,
yeah, just Yeah, right there. You know,
he's going he's going to come in and and
and immediately add size and power to
our offensive line and we'll see how he
develops. Um,
you know, one thing that caught my eye
in this last day was and really the
whole thing is how emotional and
passionate a lot of these guys were. I
know you guys could feel that on on
those Zoom calls afterwards and we
certainly felt it on the uh on the calls
when you know we talked to the guys to
tell them that they were going to become
New Orleans Saints and and uh that was
really cool.
Was there anything with the top seven
picks that surprised you or changed up
the order or anything that unexpected?
>> Um, I would say that the seven
probably went about what we expected,
not necessarily to whom we expected.
Yeah. So, there was a little bit of a
um,
you know, shuffle there just not not
amongst the names, just about who got
who ended up with whom. And like I know
a year from now it's going to be the
Thursday of the draft and everyone's
gonna say the Saints are calling.
They're the team trying to move up. Was
there anything abnormal with kind of
>> Yeah. I never made I never made one call
to move up from uh pick eight
>> which will surprise you all. I know it
was reported by a couple
>> of uh people but that was completely
untrue.
>> There were there were similar reports
about the second day. Was that a day
where you were more active or the
second? Yeah, we did we did try to move
up a little bit uh in on the second day.
Yes.
>> I guess
>> unsuccessfully as noted.
>> To clarify, teams call you about trying
to trade down to eight?
>> Yes.
>> Just to clarify, I mean, was there just
no interest in in moving up? Was it just
not a
>> Yeah, I didn't feel like uh it felt like
the cost was going to be too high um and
we were going to end up with a really
quality player. We we just liked, you
know, a lot of guys in that first group
and and we're going to be um
um pretty happy with whomever we ended
up and really happy with who we ended up
with.
>> Vicki, when you're deciding whether to
draft a guy with an injury history like
Jordan Tyson, like what is it that makes
a team comfortable with that? Is it as
simple as looking at medical records and
saying maybe this won't reoccur? How
much does a player's attitude towards? I
think it all comes into play. All of it.
All of it is, you know, all of it comes
into play. I think I think often times
you're looking for, do any of these
injuries, are they causing problems
right now? Are they symptomatic right
now? Do they keep, you know, are they
the kinds of things that are going to
keep somebody from practicing every day?
You know, is it is it a situation where
if it's a knee, does it swell up every
day? And do you have to have a lot of
rest days? um what's the what's the
likelihood of a recoccurring injury? You
know, the the one of the realities of
football is that there's a lot of
injuries in our game. Um and and guys,
you know, how resilient are they? Um so
there's a lot of variables.
>> Does he seem to have like a plan already
to take care of his body and how he
would prevent things from happening
again? Obviously, sometimes you can't,
but I don't know if you know when you
talk to him,
>> that is a factor. Yeah, that is a
factor. I I think that and and I would
say this is, you know, these guys are
young guys for the most part, right?
They're they're,
you know, 21, 22, 23 years old. Um, and
they're just learning that, you know,
some of the things that they're doing uh
off the field can impact
um, you know, their availability and and
uh, you know, a lot of guys don't learn
that until they get to the league. and
and I think we're pretty sophisticated
as a league. Our um strength and
conditioning and our performance coaches
are pretty sophisticated in terms of of
uh preventing injuries and and and doing
things that that um you know can help
you stay on the field. And so we'll help
him in that regard. And and obviously
it's important to him and that and
that's one of the things that you're
looking for. You're looking for guys
that that want to be on the field all
the time. They don't want to miss
practice. You know, they're it bothers
them um to be in the training room. So,
um yeah, they're all variables that that
we consider.
>> You joked about trading up, but it's two
years in a row now, so you guys have
made 17 picks. So, over the last two
years, I mean, was there were there
deals you would have made in the past,
the value was right and stuff, but you
you felt like compiling picks is where
this team exists right now?
>> No, I I wouldn't say it's that. I I
think
you know and look we tried in a in a
couple of cases um
but weren't weren't able to do it. You
know there it's just the circumstances
um
just weren't there for us to make a move
that
that somebody else was going to agree
to.
>> What do you like about Tyrie Wilson?
>> Yeah, look I I think look we liked him
as a player coming out. Um,
you know, I think more than anything,
Brandon has a vision for him fitting
into our defense. Um, and it adds to,
you know, a a group that we that we like
already. So, um, anxious to get him here
and and u, obviously he was a high pick
um, for the Raiders and and I'm anxious
to get him here. We liked him a lot
coming out and and still like him as a
as a professional. Is there him as a
standup pass rusher?
>> Yeah, I I think I think we've got a
couple of different ideas how to use him
and uh
>> you know, we'll see what how in this off
season and training camp uh if that
comes to fruition.
>> Does that change anything with Cam
Jordan? Are you still
>> No, I don't I don't think so. Uhuh. No.
>> Is the fifth year option something have
to look at or is that kind of already
decided?
>> Yeah. Um,
yeah, I I think he's he's going to be a
free agent after this year in all
likelihood. So, um,
yeah, I think I I don't I know exactly
the rule. I got to remember what the
date line the final date was, but
relative to him, but no, um, I think
he's going to be a free agent next year.
So, it's a one-year um, trial and and
we'll see how it goes. Did you go into
this graph kind of with the idea of of
maybe acquiring an edge through a trade
like a veteran player? Is that something
maybe like after after you take took
Jordan that that kind of crystallized?
>> Yeah, I I don't know. I wouldn't say a
plan necessarily, but we have been
talking um with the Raiders about Tyrie
for quite some time. So, it it didn't
just come up today.
You also tried to joke about the track
speed that you acquired today, but is
that coincidental or was that a a
specific emphasis?
>> No, I I think that um probably somewhere
in between, right? You always want to
add speed to your team. Um
and look, we lost, you know, Rasheed uh
last year and he was he was a that's a a
big element of his game and so we wanted
to add that. We wanted to add some
return ability. Um, we got that. So,
um, it was
it was conscious that add some speed to
our rooms.
>> Was there anyone else that was
specifically a a special teams fit that
that you've taken today? Probably.
>> Well, I think you're always, you know,
one of the considerations when you get
later in the draft is obviously the
position and the but hey, what's the
path to the roster? And often times for
guys, you know, on this day, the path to
the roster is special teams. So, um,
it's either they have experience in
their college career or they have the
traits that we think are necessary to
become effective special teams uh,
players. So, uh, that's definitely part
of the consideration of who we drafted
uh, later today.
>> Is that true of like Lorenzo Styles or
TJ Hall?
>> Absolutely. How different do you think
the offense can look next year with
everything you've done in free agency
and now the draft?
>> Yeah, I I mean that's a question for for
Kellen really. Um look, we've added, you
know, a downfield element. We've added
some size. Um
you know, but you know, we'll see. We'll
see how that goes.
>> With Jordan and and uh Bryce in
particular, how do those guys and their
skill sets complement what you already
have in that room? Yeah, I think again
we just, you know, we're adding talent
to the room. We're adding a
developmental 63,
you know, 44 player that that uh, you
know, played at he didn't play at a
power four conference. He played, you
know, he played for North Dakota State.
And so there's probably some development
that we need to do there. Um, you know,
Jordan Tyson obviously, you know, he
he's got a complimentary skill set to
Chris, um, the guys that we have, Devon,
some of the other guys we have. So,
look, it's a good mix right now. We
just, we were just talking about it.
>> Jim Miller, just what you like from him
and why at that spot specifically.
>> Yeah, again, you know, big
uh we're going to look pretty good
coming off the bus, I think.
Um,
but big powerful, you know, young man
and and uh adds to adds to a great room.
And so,
>> yeah, we were excited to get him.
>> You didn't I'm sorry. You didn't early
in this draft add uh a guy for Alante
Taylor's the the spot that obviously
opens up on the defense. Did you feel
good about what you already had in house
to fill that spot and that's why you
didn't or did you? No, I I think we
probably if in a perfect world, we went
into the draft thinking, you know, we
wanted to get uh a guy in the early part
of the uh draft at that position. Um but
it just didn't work out.
>> Is Lorenzo a spot to kind of fill that
spot or
>> Yeah, I I think you know a developmental
player. Yeah, for sure. Um to you know,
Brandon refers to these guys as DBs more
than corners, nickels, or safeties. And
so, uh, I'm going to take that tact and
and just say, "Hey, look, we added some
DBs, some of which are a little more
developmental, and we've got to wait
till we get into training camp to see
how they fit with the defense that that
um, Brandon wants to play."
>> All get sorted out, you know, throughout
the offseason, but you've got 14
receivers now, and that includes some of
the guys that are also essentially
rookies in Jaylen P and Trey Palmer. I
mean, was there a was there a point
where overcrowding was a discussion?
>> Yeah, we we've talked about that and,
you know, as we get, you know, as we get
some of these undrafted free agents
signed and we we take a step back,
we're, you know, we're probably going to
have to adjust some numbers in some
different areas and um, yeah, we're a
little heavy in that in that group
relative to the 90man roster right now.
Lorenzo talked about his uh post
postcombine procedure but mentioned that
he would
>> who did Lorenzo.
>> Oh yeah that he expects that he'll be
ready for training camp. Is that the
same timeline that that you're offering?
>> Yeah I think I think probably I don't
know that we expect him to be ready at
the beginning of training camp but uh
certainly during uh the course of
training camp we we're you know really
well aware of of his timeline and and
feel pretty pretty good about it. With
Barryian being right down the road, were
you able to maybe key in on his ability
a little more than other guys? Is that
possible?
>> Yeah. Um yes, because look, we went up
to the proday. Uh we had him here for
our local proday. Um really enjoyed our
visits with him and and and uh he did a
good job in their proday, too. And man,
he was enthusiastic when we called him.
Uh it was it was fun to it was fun to
feel that excitement from him. And um
yeah, I just remember his comment. We
were talking to him about about his
speed and during the uh local local uh
um pro day afterwards and one of the
comments he made was he never lost a
race and I thought, "Oh, that's pretty
good."
>> You kind of mentioned it before, but
with
>> Jordan, like you know, at the time there
were still some prominent defenders on
the board. just what was it about Jordan
that you felt like you really wanted to
pick offense there rather than go
>> well there's nothing about about uh the
rest of the guys that you know this is
man there was some really good options
for us um but we just felt like you know
given where we're at and the talent
level this was this was you know the guy
for us and uh we really excited to get
him. I would say that
pre-draft,
um, when you, you know, consider where
other guys are likely to go, um, we felt
really good about about, uh, Jordan
Tyson being the being our pick and
excited that he was available to us.
when you talked about like uh being risk
adverse a little bit in terms of your
pre-draft press conference um with him I
mean I know you're comfortable enough to
draft him with the injury history but
like
>> was that ever like a I guess do you see
it as a risk at all like how do you kind
of square with that? I I think when you
look at all these players, there's
there's some risk, right? Um and we all
have a vision. We're projecting them as
to what they can be in our league. And
so there's there's risk with every guy.
And some of it is um more scheme fit.
Some of it may be um you know the just
the physical attributes and and with him
there was you know he's missed some
games. Um but we you know dove pretty
deep into that um into that uh history
and at the end of it we felt
comfortable.
>> If you had to say the one thing about
Jordan that set him apart for you, was
there something about his skill set that
you liked enough to get him at a
>> Yeah, I mean I think there's a lot of
things. He, you know, fast, twitchy,
tough, you know, he he uh
he stops well, you know, he he he uh uh
he's just got a lot of a lot of great
skills. Um a lot of his catches are
first downs and touchdowns. Uh he makes
tough catches. So there's just the whole
package really. And and look, if you're
going to be a top 10 pick in our league,
you better have the whole package. And
that's for every position.
>> Coach Dillingham talked about his
competitiveness. Was that that stood out
to y'all?
>> Yeah, absolutely. Uh uh absolutely.
>> And you feel it when you talk with him.
>> Four of your top five draft picks were
on offense and the two highest paid free
agents that you signed were on offense
coming out of the season. Was that we
we've got to invest in this offense?
Like has this been a mission since
January? Yeah, I I think when you know
when you go through that u postseason
evaluation
and you start looking at okay here's
here's the holes that we need to fill.
Here's where we need to significantly
get better must needs and wants. There
was just more on offense as it as it
turned out. And so um you know some
years it's it's it's offense and some
years it's defense. So this year it was
offense.
>> Y'all got a lot taller at wide receiver
since last year. Was that a was that a
you know active plan? Is that just kind
of how it happened?
>> Uh a little bit. Yeah. You know, size is
good in the NFL, right?
>> Did uh how much did Tyler's uh stretch
last year kind of influence, you know,
what you think you could need on offense
and like the acquisitions you made to to
try and help him, I guess.
>> Yeah. I Well, I don't know that I don't
know that I would say it like t you
know, Tyler's influence. every
quarterback in our league, you know,
wants and needs weapons, right? They
need guys uh to get the ball to and
hopefully they can do something special
with it. And so, I don't think it's
unique to Tyler, but I do think that u
you know, we needed to we knew we needed
to add in that area. Um and you know,
hopefully we have.
>> Now that you've added nine guys, will
you be able to narrow your focus for
whatever's left to be done in free
agency? Yeah, I think I think for uh
yes, we'll you know reassess the roster
um in the next coming weeks and
you know what always happens with this
is that you know teams add players and
you know there's other guys veteran guys
that may become available through trade.
So we'll you know we'll take a look at
that along with the guys that are still
free agents. Uh Del didn't put up like a
bunch of big receiving numbers at at
Georgia, but can you like can you
project more there like some some kind
of untapped receiving potential from
what you saw on tape? Yeah, I think you
know our guys would say and we would all
say that he's got all the traits you
know necessary to to be really
productive in the pass game and he's a
really willing and able um blocker and
so we felt like u giving us some help as
a you know white tight end it would be
important and you know he he's was very
resilient uh at Georgia you know that's
a tough program those coaches just do a
great job and they're really tough um on
their players and he was really
resilient and and stayed the whole time
and was was a really good player for
them and and they were really
complimentary about about him. So, we
were surprised that he was available to
us. Um,
you know, when we took him and I
wouldn't say that we went into the draft
thinking, man, we got to get a tight
end, but at some point the value just,
you know, jumps out at you.
>> And that was like kind of during a
stretch when like a bunch of tight ends
started going. They
>> sure did.
>> Were you kind of getting a little maybe
nervous right before? I I don't I
wouldn't say nervous, but you know that
that's the area every year that you know
the tight end seemed to go right in that
that you know window that third fourth
round uh you know window. So it wasn't a
surprise.
>> Did the pass rushers going in round two
before you guys influence what you did
at um formally or I guess
>> um
I I don't know that I would say it that
way. It's just that I would say that um
you know the strength of this draft
wasn't in big people, right? U didn't
seem like there was as many as it
normally is. So, you know, that became a
little bit more of a premium, but you
know, we liked we liked him from the
beginning. He was, you know, highly
graded guy for us and and excited to get
him.
um not picking a running back, does that
impact Alvin one way or another or would
you guys want to do there?
>> Yeah, well, you know, we'll we'll see
what happens here in the next few weeks,
but um yeah, we didn't we didn't go into
the draft thinking, you know, we had to
go get a running back either.
>> Would you like that settled before like
onfield work begins?
>> Yeah, I mean, I don't know that I would
characterize it that way. We'll we'll
just see what happens
>> with um Dell often the leap for a tight
end from college that pros is
complicated with protections we hear a
lot with because of the program that he
was a part of. Do you think that he's a
little bit further along than your
typical draft prospect?
>> Um yeah, I I would say he probably is.
Uh and he's he's a you know, smart kid,
really smart kid, and I don't think he's
going to have any problems, you know,
learning our scheme.
um with Garrett uh falling the way that
he did. I mean,
>> yeah,
>> your last pick there, did you give it a
consideration or was it
>> um
>> what you make of just
>> Yeah, I mean, we we we talked about that
a little a little bit. Just I I feel for
him, you know, he's a great kid. He's a
really really good player. I was really
I think we were all really surprised um
that he didn't get taken a lot earlier.
I don't know the reason behind it. Um,
and really excited when he got when he
got drafted. You know, it's a great
family and and he's going to be
successful. I'm 100% confident. And I'm
also, you know, excited for him as to
where he went cuz he probably went to
about the best place he could go to.
with um Wilson going back to him with
the success you guys had with Chase
Young like kind of
>> getting back to his career. Did that
influence your thinking on you know
wanting to take another shot on one of
these guys or
>> a little bit. Yeah, a little bit. Yeah.
Look, I think I think often times, you
know, you're looking you there's high
expectations for these guys that come
drafted early, right? High expectations.
And if they don't necessarily meet that
expectation, but they're still good
players, um, you know, they can have a a
second chance and have a really good,
you know, career and and maybe reach
reach a higher level of success. So
hopefully that's what happens here.
>> You feel good about what you got done at
this place?
>> Yes. But I always feel good about it.
I'm glass half full day, right? So, yes,
I'm feel really good about about the
group. It was a perfect no. It didn't
come out perfect in terms of what we
might have laid out prior to the draft,
but it was really good. And it never
comes out perfect. So, yeah, we're
excited. We're excited to get these guys
in here. Uh excited to get them in for
that first rookie mini camp and and then
get going. When you had this many draft
picks and you go to sign the undrafted
free agents,
>> do you still look at needs at all or can
you pretty much just zero in on the guys
who are the highest rated?
>> Um, it's a good question and I would say
that it's a combination of the two.
We've got to fill out the roster, right?
Um, we've got to have a certain number
at every position and we pay attention
to that. But it if for example, and this
is just hypothetical, it's not real. If
for example, we were full at safety, but
we had a really high highly graded
safety out there available to us, we'd
go one over in that area and and go
short someplace else because of of the
um of the grade. So, it's a combination
of the two. You guys are almost I mean
you still have a little bit of wiggle
room with the 90 man, but does that kind
of impact how active you'll be with
>> Yeah, I mean we're going to end up with
um 10 maybe
um a fewer number than most years.
>> Yeah. um with picking up that 219th
overall selection late and then going
with with TJ Hall, what was it that you
guys liked about him at that area and
and kind of how do you go about you know
kind of being ready for that situation?
Yeah, I I think that um look, that was
part of the the trade obviously and
there was, you know, that's a value
proposition. you know,
we they had a certain value they wanted
for um Tyrie and we wanted to pay a
certain value and it just worked out
that we ended up back with that pick
where we traded down and uh
and uh so you get that pick and then all
of a sudden, man, here's a player that
we were considering at the bottom of the
fifth round and the sixth round and man,
he's still there. So, it was kind of
like a no-brain for us. Um, you know,
play played at Iowa, played at a high
level. Um, that's a really good program.
He's well coached and it's a guy we can
throw at it at at the at a couple
positions because he's he's we think
he's a pretty versatile athlete and we
might have a swing at three different
spots for him.
>> You should try that again next year. See
how you like
>> is uh
>> Yeah.
>> Is Jeremiah right? Um,
does is he only a guard or can he play
center at all or or will you try him
there?
>> I think look, we'd be doing him a
disservice to try to play him at
multiples positions right now. So, we're
going to start him at at guard and let's
just go from there.
>> All right. Thank you guys.